Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
I can't believe there was a survivor.
His body is incredibly strong.
The Gatlantis ship was blown to pieces, right?
There are signs of artificial modification in its DNA.
Maybe he's not a simple humanoid, but...
An artificial life-form, like a synthetic soldier ?
Did you see them while you were
aboard the Yamato, Miss Niimi ?
I saw them, but...
Hold on. I'll get some documents.
Garmillas Empire Earth Embassy
It's confirmed, Ambassador !
A surviving Gatlantis soldier is being
held at an Earth Force research facility !
Make them stop at once !
Pressure's rising inside the capsule !
It's dangerous !
What's going on ?
It's boiling ! Release the valve !
There's no time !
People around the whole world, as the
first president of the Earth Federation...
...I hereby declare the completion
of the latest Andromeda class ships.
Earth Federation Defense Force Adromeda Class
Ship 3 - Apollo Norm
Ship 4 - Achilles
Ship 2 - Aldebaran
Ship 5 - Antares
The alliance between Earth and Garmillas is a strength that will bring peace to the universe and maintain it.
As the symbol of assuming such a heavy responsibility, ship No.1 has already...
Why didn't you tell us about the survivor ?
Gatlantis soldiers will self-destruct unless a certain treatment is made to the body.
That's how they're created.
If you had informed us...
With all due respect, your disclosure
of such important information now is like...
Are you blaming us ?
If you had told us about it before the joint operation...
We had unfortunate misunderstandings in
the past, but Earth and Garmillas are now allies.
I believe we're equal partners.
Earth's current population is 1/3 of its peak time.
Even if Garmillas is in turmoil
after the collapse of the Desler regime...
...you could easily invade us if you were so inclined.
Obviously, that shouldn't happen, but...
I know it's paranoia because
we have an equivalent word.
My advice is that you're playing with fire.
You broke a promise with Iscandar,
which is what saved you.
Right. That was just a verbal agreement that
the captain of a spaceship made on his own.
It wasn't a treaty or the
wish of the Earth government.
These are ?
The former crew of the Yamato.
They could have heard the voice of Teresa,
although I have no confirmation.
They did ?
The Earth government is aware of it, too.
I want to talk to them in person before the information gets leaked from the Garmillas home planet.
He's the earthling who attempted to stop
that huge Gatlantis battleship with a tiny ship.
Grand Court of Inquiry
If Telezart is involved, the matter is very serious.
Maybe he can...
“Thank you for your service.”
They chewed you out ?
Quite a lot. "Do you understand the
implications of your actions ?" they asked.
"I saved Earth, so what ?"
Nah, I couldn't say that.
Go ahead and say it. Nobody is listening.
Kodai Susumu saved Earth !
You'd better thank him ! This's the second time !
Hey !
Mori Yuki was worried !
My apologies.
Kodai Susumu deeply regrets it.
Planned Power Outage
Lifted for the Area
of Expansion
Gami Get the hell out!!
Amazing, isn't it ?
I feel like I'm back on old Earth.
Do you remember...
Oh, I'm sorry.
What about you ? Are you alright ?
Any anxiety about having a wife
with only four years of memories ?
The memories of the past
four years are all that we need.
The voyage to Iscandar and the
remaining three years weren't so easy.
It's not easy even today.
But we're alive.
Kodai ?
Let's just look ahead.
We will be happy for sure.
It's the duty of those who have survived...
Kodai...
I'm already happy.
Captain Okita, look at those colorful cities.
The battle against Garmillas feels like a dream.
Drink up, Captain.
Today is your third anniversary.
Earth has changed, building large cities and a
number of huge battleships with wave motion guns.
I'm fine with restoration,
but I must doubt its direction.
Nobody looks back at the Yamato,
which housed the Cosmo Reverse.
Okita, looks like we're the only
ones who remember that battle.
Dr. Sado.
You're all here.
Hey !
What took you so long ?
Sorry.
Kodai.
Shima, it's been a while.
I heard you put on a flashy show again.
The entire transport fleet is buzzing about that.
All hands, line up !
Captain, all those on Earth are here.
They're committed to restoring Earth
in each of their fields, so please rest easy.
Give a salute to the soul of Okita Juzo,
the great captain of the Yamato !
Kodai...
...I'm sorry for making you assume all the responsibility.
It's okay.
I'm concerned about something.
Immediately after that incident, there was a
communication failure throughout the Solar System.
Right.
We don't know what caused it, but...
Kodai, who did you see at that moment ?
Kodai, get on board the Yamato.
It was my deceased father,
for the first time in ten years.
He was a man of few words as before.
I saw someone, too.
I saw my father.
He clearly urged me to
get on board the Yamato.
I did, too.
Me too.
What are the odds ?
It must have targeted the former Yamato crew.
A lot of people saw a similar
vision at the exact same moment...
...and the military seems to have
begun its own investigation.
The military has ?
A fleet of ships with wave motion guns,
and unrealistic recovery plans...
What the Yamato brought back wasn't
meant to build this kind of Earth.
It feels like the Yamato became pessimistic
about the future of Earth and called upon us.
The Yamato did...
Kodai, who was in your vision ?
I didn't see anybody.
It's the Andromeda !
That's the first ship.
Screw you !
I have something I want both of you to see.
What's this comet-like object ?
It's an unknown quasar.
After making spatial corrections, we
discovered that it's approaching Earth...
...at near light-speed.
It's a concern, but it's not expected to reach the
Earth sector until tens of thousands of years from now.
The bigger problem is the energy
wave which made us see that vision.
It became clear that the wave was emitted
from almost the same direction as this quasar.
It was clearly directed at Earth
with extreme directional accuracy.
It somehow influenced our consciousness
and made us see people from the past.
Precisely.
The thing is, the Yamato's recorder had a log...
...and I was able to sneak it
out before the military took it.
I'm going to extract the data.
What the...?
The data is going out of control.
Warriors of a distant planet....
...all of you and everything else...
You saw her, didn't you, Shima ?
It was a person.
A prayer.
She was asking for help.
You saw her, right, Sanada ?
We have to go to this location.
Right there.
Watch it !
Kodai, calm down.
I agree with Kodai's opinion.
I don't have any reason, but she made
us see that vision, which shook our hearts.
We have been called upon...
...by an unknown entity in the universe.
Our hearts understand that.
We should go...
...regardless of who the person is, or wherever it is.
Captain Okita must have wanted to say that.
If someone in the universe needs our help, we must...
Kodai...
Shima, don't you see ?
A sailor must not abandon
those who are in need of help.
Your father would say the same thing.
The reason isn't strong enough to take any action.
Only you can pilot the Yamato !
Several hundred former crewmen of the
Yamato have received the same message.
The military won't be able to ignore it.
If we bring this to them...
If the military was that flexible,
I wouldn't have quit the military.
You're not alone anymore, right ?
Think about Miss Mori, too.
Former Far East Command HQ
You've been under surveillance.
Along with the rest of the Yamato crew.
Under surveillance ?
You should have some idea why.
Who are you ?
A Garmillan...
This humidity is terrible.
In a place like this, you earthlings are so...
I'm not asking you to forget about the past. The war also took many lives on our end.
But Garmillas owes a lot to the Yamato,
and I want to pay off that debt.
I invite you to the Moon.
The Moon ?
To the Garmillas Embassy on the Moon.
Earth Federation Defense Force's Next Primary Fighter
Cosmo Tiger II
Guys, you have...
...only fifteen seconds left.
Prototype Fighter
Cosmo Tiger I
Can't you even leave a scratch ?
You're wasting a superior new fighter.
Five...
...four...
...three...
...two...
Time's up.
Tsurumi, you're dead again.
Dammit !
You can't be so pathetic
in front of Instructor Kato.
Instructor Yamamoto's so tough.
This is the third time this month that
Instructor Kato has had to take a leave.
His son's illness is that bad ?
It's because of the space radiation sickness.
It's congenital ?
Yeah.
Makoto thinks it's her fault.
A sanatorium on the Moon
can slow down the progress.
I'm sure they're desperate.
Susumu Kodai
Kodai...?
When the freighter reaches Moon orbit...
...you descend to the Moon's surface
along with the purged cargo boxes.
Remember, the Embassy is guarded with a
number of unmanned anti-terrorism weapons.
Meet Ambassador Barrel.
You'll learn the truth about your vision.
This concerns the future of both Earth and Garmillas.
This is the first step.
Don't let carelessness kill you.
Klaus Keyman...
Liaison my ass...
Right now, I must move forward.
This is Yamamoto Akira of the Cosmo
Tiger Team, hailing the Moon Command HQ.
I accidentally encroached on
Garmillas Embassy airspace.
Tell them that it was accidental, and issue an apology.
Be safe.
Your Majesty Zorder, we've identified
the destination of Teresa's cosmo wave.
It's a very remote planet.
One of our vanguard fleet's
vessels went missing there.
I presume it's the home planet of those
who've formed an alliance with Garmillas.
Earth, huh ?
His Majesty has made a decision.
Gatlantis Empire, move forward !
Episode 02
Tense Infiltration into the Embassy on the Moon
Sono hito no yasashisa ga hana ni masaru nara
If that person's gentleness exceeds that of the flowers
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Yamamoto Akira:
Niimi Kaoru:
Tsurumi Jiro:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Chiba Yuki
Tanaka Rie
Hisakawa Aya
Kawamoto Keiji
Okita Juzo:
Todou Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Zorder:
Sabera:
Barrel:
Keyman:
Teresa:
President:
Researcher A:
Researcher B:
Sugao Takayuki
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Tezuka Hideaki
Kaida Yuko
Tersoma Masaki
Kamiya Hiroshi
Kanda Sayaka
Mikimoto Yuji
Fujinuma Kento
Mogi Takamasa
Sono hito no utsukushisa ga hoshi ni masaru nara
If that person's beauty exceeds that of the stars
Kimi wa te wo hirogete mamoru ga ii
You had better open your arms and offer protection
Karada wo nagedasu neuchi ga aru
It's worth risking your life
Hitori hitori ga omou koto wa ai suru hito no tame dake de ii
Each of you had better think about the person you love
Kimi ni hanasu koto ga aru toshitara ima wa sore dake kamo shirenai
If there's anything I can say, perhaps that's all for now
Ima wa saraba to iwasenai de kure
Don't make me say goodbye for now
Don't make me say goodbye for now.
Preview
Those who are called on by Teresa...
You must have been suspicious about the
unusually fast completion of the Andromeda.
...re-equip the wave motion gun.
Is this really a rebuild ?
Is this alright ?
Everyone, I need your help !
Astonishing Legacy of the Cosmo Reverse
Episode 03